Guide to the Rudolf Carnap Papers, 1904-2007 ASP.1974.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Rudolf Carnap Papers
1904-2007
1920-1970
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Carnap, Rudolf, 1891-1970
ASP.1974.01
44.5 Linear Feet
Rudolf Carnap made substantial contributions in the areas of constructional theories, physicalism, the epistemological foundations of physics and mathematics, the syntactical structure of language, semantics, modal logic, and probability theory. Throughout his career he stressed the importance of formal analysis as the key to solving philosophical problems. His papers include extensive correspondence covering his entire life and career, lecture outlines for courses that he taught in Vienna, Prague, and the U.S.; and manuscript drafts and typescripts both for his published works and for many unpublished writings. Digital reproductions of this collection are available online.
Biography
Born in 1891 in Ronsdorf, Germany, Rudolf Carnap was educated at the Universities of Freiburg and Jena. He studied mathematics, philosophy, and physics, completing his doctoral thesis, Der Raum, in 1921. Before immigrating to America in 1935, Carnap held positions in Vienna and Prague, where he laid the foundations for his own logical empiricism and participated actively in the discussions of the Vienna Circle. After arriving in the United States, Carnap taught at the University of Chicago until 1952, was a fellow at the Institute for Advanced Study from 1952 to 1954, and held a position at UCLA from 1954 until his death in 1970.
Carnap made substantial contributions in the areas of constructional theories, physicalism, the epistemological foundations of physics and mathematics, the syntactical structure of language, semantics, modal logic, and probability theory. Throughout his career he stressed the importance of formal analysis as the key to solving philosophical problems.
Scope and Content Notes
The Carnap Papers contain some 10,000 pages of letters to and from Carnap, which cover his entire life and career. Since Carnap relied heavily on the mail to discuss important philosophical problems, he corresponded with hundreds of other scholars, among them Herbert Feigl, Carl Gustav Hempel, Felix Kaufmann, Otto Neurath, and Moritz Schlick. A substantial collection of photographs taken throughout Carnap's life depicts him, his relatives, and a number of thinkers with whom he worked closely.
Among Carnap's student notes, perhaps the most interesting come from his seminars with Frege, which were devoted to the Begriffsschrift and the role of logic in mathematics. Also available are Carnap's notes from Russell's seminar at Chicago and notes he took from discussions with Quine, Tarski, Gödel, Hempel, Jeffrey, Heisenberg, and many others.
More than 1,000 pages of lecture outlines for courses that Carnap taught in Vienna, Prague, and the U.S. trace his development as a teacher. Moreover, the collection includes manuscript drafts and typescripts both for his published works and for many unpublished papers and books. In addition, two unpublished papers represent first formulations of Carnap's Aufbau. "Quasizerlegung" ("Quasianalysis," 1932, 21 pp.) outlines the analytical methods for defining quality classes, and "Vom Chaos zur Wirklichkeit" ("From Chaos to Reality," 1922, 14 pp.) represents his first attempt at a construction system using more than six basic relations, instead of one as in the Aufbau. "Topologie der Raum-Zeit-Welt" (Topology of the Space-Time World, 1924) is Carnap's 104-page attempt at a logical reconstruction of the space-time framework of modern physics without using numbers. These are only a few examples of Carnap's many unpublished papers.
The paper's correspondence and manuscripts measure 44.5 linear feet. Much material is written in an outdated German shorthand (the Stolze-Schrey system), which Carnap used extensively since his student days.
Acquisition Information
The papers were acquired from Carnap's daughter Hanna Carnap-Thost in 1974.
Arrangement
The Rudolf Carnap Papers are arranged into 28 series. Detailed scope and content notes can be found at each series level. When the Carnap Papers were initially processed, the intention was to preserve as much as possible Carnap's original filing system (and occasionally lack thereof) as to the order, content, and titles of the file folders. Therefore, unrelated items may appear in series groupings. In addition, some series may partially repeat in subject matter or format.
Series I. Personal Documents, 1914-1970
Series II. Work in Probability (see also related material in series X), 1946-1970
Series III. Carnap's Death, Politics, Graphology: Notes, Clippings, and Correspondence, 1923-1971
Series IV. Photographs
Series V. Correspondence and Diaries, 1908-1970
Series VI. Induction and Probability, 1933-1958
Series VII. Notes and Correspondence of Later Years and Manuscripts on Entropy, 1954-1970
Series VIII. Early Manuscripts, Politische Rundbriefe, and Vienna Circle Records, 1908-1969
Series IX. Reviews of Carnap's Work, 1934-1969
Series X. Studies in Inductive Logic and Probability: Drafts, Discussions, Correspondence (see also related material in series II), 1948-1970
Series XI. Financial Information and Ina Documents, 1904-1969
Series XII. Notes and Correspondence: Probability, Mathematics, Publishers, UCLA Administrative, and Lecture Notes, 1927-1970
Series XIII. "An Axiom System of Inductive Logic" and Schilpp Replies: Ditto Material for Distribution, 1952-1965
Series XIV. Correspondence with Philosophy Authors, 1930-1970
Series XV. Language Systems, Semantics, Value Theory, Logical Modalities, 1932-1962
Series XVI. Publications, Interviews, and Lectures Notes, 1903-1969
Series XVII. Correspondence with Individuals, Organizations, and Institutions, 1930-1970
Series XVIII. Probability Problems, 1952-1962
Series XIX. Health, Travel, Retirement, Books, and Politics, 1937-1970
Series XX. Probability Problems, International Language, and Philosophy of Physics, 1952-1962
Series XXI. Correspondence with Individuals, 1921-1970
Series XXII. Card Files
Series XXIII. "An Axiom System of Inductive Logic" (AS): Drafts and Dittos, 1959-1965
Series XXIV. Publications, Dissertations, and Lecture Notes, 1910-1970
Series XXV. Annotated Books of Carnap's Library
Series XXVI. Card Files
Series XXVII. Supplementary Carnap Material with Varied Provenance, 1913-2007
Series XXVIII. Name Index
Access Restrictions
Some documents relating to medical, financial, and personal information are restricted and noted in the folder title.
Previous Citation
Rudolf Carnap Papers, 1905-1970, ASP.1974.01, Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library.
Related Material
Rudolf Carnap Papers at the University of California at Los Angeles: http://oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/tf7q2nb520
Existence and Location of Copies
A microfilm copy of the papers exist in Archives & Special Collections and in the Philosophical Archives at the University of Konstanz in Germany. Digital reproductions of this collection are available online.
Vienna circle; Semantics (Philosophy); Logical positivism -- History -- 20th century; Logical positivism; Science -- Philosophy -- History -- 20th century; Science -- Philosophy -- History -- Sources; Science -- Philosophy; Analysis (Philosophy); Philosophy; Reichenbach, Hans; Quine, W. V. (Willard Van Orman); Popper, Karl R. (Karl Raimund); Kaufmann, Felix; Morris, Charles W. (Charles William); Næss, Arne; Neurath, Otto; Ogden, C. K. (Charles Kay); Carnap, Rudolf, 1891-1970; Kaplan, David (David Benjamin); Hempel, Carl G. (Carl Gustav); Gödel, Kurt; Flitner, Wilhelm; Feigl, Herbert; Bar-Hillel, Yehoshua; Stegmüller, Wolfgang; Schlick, Moritz
- Personal Documents, 1914-1970; I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  This series comprises a variety of documents ranging from Carnap's early diaries, recording his experiences as a soldier during World War I, to European travel brochures from the late 1960s, political newspaper clippings, and administrative material concerning Carnap's late years at UCLA.
  - Testament - Elizabeth Ina Carnap's Will, 1968 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Documents R.C. and Ina-Old (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Consumer Coop., 1966 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Travel, Europa-Reise, Prospekte, 1965-1967 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Duplication Procedures, 1966 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Carnap Kriegstagebuch, 1914-1920 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Rockefeller Foundation: Villa Serbelloni, 1967 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - VEV: Newspaperclippings, 1928-1966 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - NSF Research Project "Further Development of a Theory of Inductive Probability", 1964 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Carnap's Various Letterheads and Envelopes (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Students UCLA, Article and Letter on Mexico, 1970 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Regents UCLA: A. Davis and Other Material, 1968-1970 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Cards: Addresses, Bibliographic, Library, Thank you, Calling Cards (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Tape Recordings: Briefe nur (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Catalog and Handbooks: UCLA Faculty, Research, UCLA Catalog, 1960-1969 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Medical Expenses, 1970 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Medical Expenses, 1962 (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Medical Expenses, 1963 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Medical Expenses, 1964 (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Medical Expenses, 1965 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Medical Bills (Dependents) [CLOSED], 1967 (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - Medical Expenses (R.C.), 1967 (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - Medical Expenses, 1967-1968 (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - Medical Expenses, 1969 (Box 18, Folder 24)
  - Academic Senate, 1969-1970 (Box 18, Folder 25)
  - Academic Senate: Letters and Reports, 1969 (Box 18, Folder 26)
  - Academic Senate, 1969 (Box 18, Folder 27)
- Work in Probability (see also related material in series X), 1946-1970; II.
  See also:
  Related Material in series X.
  - Studies in Inductive Logic and Probability: Notes, Manuscripts, and Correspondence, 1946-1970; 1.
    Scope and Content Notes: Featured here are drafts, notes, and correspondence relating to Carnap's "The Basic System of Inductive Logic," but also material reflecting his overall editorial work for Studies in Inductive Logic and Probability together with Richard Jeffrey, and drafts by other contributing authors.
    - Carnap & Bar-Hillel: "An Outline of a Theory of Semantic Information," Ozalid Master Sheets, 1952 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Notes for Typing Mss., 1946-1967 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Notes for Printer and Proof Reading, 1946-1967 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Undistributed Mimeo Copies of "Basic System", 1970 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - "Basic Assumptions about Individuals, Attributes and Relations": Spare Sections and Pages (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - "Basic System § 6" (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - AS Notes (old), 1958-1966 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - "Basic System of Inductive Logic": Extra Pages (ditto) (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Ms. AS: Terminology and Notation, 1959-1966 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - "Basic System of Inductive Logic": Section 18 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - "An Axiom System of Inductive Logic": Fifth (and Last) Part, §18 "Lambda-Families", 1964 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - BS: §17A (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - BS: §17 B & C (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - AS, §18, cont., pp. 406-448 (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - "An Axiom System of Inductive Logic," Ditto Masters §18, pp. 406-450 (Item 1a), 1964 (Box 19, Folder 15a)
    - "An Axiom System of Inductive Logic," Ditto Masters, §18, pp. 406-450 (Item 1b), 1964 (Box 19, Folder 15b)
    - "An Axiom System of Inductive Logic," Ditto Masters, §18 (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - BS Notes (2): Nicht für Ms! (Items 1-22), 1961-1970 (Box 19, Folder 17a)
    - BS Notes (2): Nicht für Ms! (Items 23-31), 1931-1970 (Box 19, Folder 17b)
    - Jeffery, Richard: Correspondence "Basic System", 1969-1970 (Box 19, Folder 18)
    - Gaifman, Haim: Correspondence Ms. Art. 5 "Application of de Finetti's Theorem to Inductive Logic", 1970 (Box 19, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence with Jeffrey & Zachary on Studies in Inductive Logic and Probability, Vol. 1, 1969-1970 (Box 19, Folder 20)
    - Inductive Logic and Rational Decisions: Article 1 "Decision Making", 1969 (Box 19, Folder 21)
    - Ms. by Richard Jeffrey: "Probability Measures and Integrals," Article 3 (Item 1a), 1970 (Box 19, Folder 22a)
    - Ms. by Richard Jeffrey: "Probability Measures and Integrals," Article 3 (Item 1b), 1970 (Box 19, Folder 22b)
    - "Series of Predicates" VIII, 1960 and 1963 (Box 19, Folder 23)
    - Fragmented Ms. Pages for "Basic System" (Box 19, Folder 24)
    - Series of Predicates IX, 1965-1969 (Box 19, Folder 25)
    - Carnap: "Principle of Analogy in Two Families," with Corrections by Peter Krauss, 1962 (Box 19, Folder 26)
    - Basic System Notes Current (Items 1-25), 1960-1970 (Box 19, Folder 27a)
    - Basic System Notes Current (Items 26-45), 1959-1969 (Box 19, Folder 27b)
    - Ms. Jürgen Humburg: "The Principle of Instantial Relevance" and Carnap "On Extensibility", 1970 (Box 19, Folder 28)
    - Jürgen Humburg: "The Principle of Instantial Relevance" Article 4, and Carnap TS "On Extensibility: Some Further Remarks on the Jeffrey-Humburg Ms for Article 4", 1970 (Box 19, Folder 29)
    - Carnap: "Inductive Logic and Rational Decision", 1969 (Box 19, Folder 30)
    - Carnap:"Basic System" Ditto Masters: §4 "Pure and Applied Inductive Logic", 1969 (Box 19, Folder 31)
    - Basic System Bibliography (Items 1-6), 1969-1970 (Box 19, Folder 32a)
    - Basic System Bibliography (Items 7-12), 1969-1970 (Box 19, Folder 32b)
    - Axiom System §18: Extra Sheets (Item 1) (Box 19, Folder 33a)
    - Axiom System §18: Extra Sheets (Item 2) (Box 19, Folder 33b)
    - Mimeo Copy of Basic System: 2. Individual Attributes (Item 1) (Box 19, Folder 34a)
    - Mimeo Copy of Basic System: 3. Models and Propositions (Item 2) (Box 19, Folder 34b)
    - Mimeo Copy of Basic System: 1. Basic Concepts and Basic Axioms (Items 3-6) (Box 19, Folder 34c)
    - Mimeo Copy of Basic System: 4. Pure and Applied Inductive Logic (Item 7) (Box 19, Folder 34d)
    - Mimeo Copy of Basic System: 14. Attribute Space (Item 8) (Box 19, Folder 34e)
    - Mimeo Copy of Basic System: 15. Basic Regions in the Attribute Space (Item 9) (Box 19, Folder 34f)
    - Mimeo Copy of Basic System: 16. The Analogy Influence (Item 10) (Box 19, Folder 34g)
    - Mimeo Copy of Basic System: 17. The Eta-Function (Item 11) (Box 19, Folder 34h)
    - Addresses for Basic System (Box 19, Folder 35)
  - Basic System of Inductive Logic, Manuscript Drafts, 1968-1969; 2.
    Subseries 2 represents manuscript drafts for part 2 of Carnap's work "Basic System of Inductive Logic," which was published posthumously in volume II of Studies in Inductive Logic and Probability in 1980, edited by Richard Jeffrey.
    - §14 A, B, C "The Attribute Space; Distances and Width of Attributes," Ditto Master, 1968-1969 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - §15 "Basic Regions and Admissible Regions in the Attribute Space," Ditto Master (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - §16 "The Analogy Influence," Ditto Master (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - §17 A, B, C "The Eta Function," Ditto Master (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - §18 "Some Special Kinds of Families," Ditto Master (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - §1-4B, Ditto Master (Item 1a), 1968 (Box 20, Folder 6a)
    - §1-4B, Ditto Master (Item 1b), 1968 (Box 20, Folder 6b)
    - §5-9, Ditto Master (Item 1a) (Box 20, Folder 7a)
    - §5-9, Ditto Master (Item 1b) (Box 20, Folder 7b)
    - §10, 11 A, B, C, Ditto Master (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - §12, 13, Ditto Master (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - §14 "The Attribute Space; Distance and Widths of Attributes", 1968 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - §15 "Basic Regions and Admissable Regions in the Attribute Space", 1969 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - §16 "The Analogy Influence", 1969 (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - §17 "The Eta Function", November 1969 - April 1970 (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - §18 "Some Special Kinds of Families", 1970 (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - §1-§4 "Basic Concepts and Basic Axioms" (Item 1a), 1959-1969 (Box 20, Folder 15a)
    - §1-§4 "Basic Concepts and Basic Axioms" (Item 1b), 1959-1969 (Box 20, Folder 15b)
    - §5 "Basic Assumptions about Individuals, Attributes, and Relations" (Item 1a), 1968 (Box 20, Folder 16a)
    - §5 "Basic Assumptions about Individuals, Attributes, and Relations" (Item 1b), 1968 (Box 20, Folder 16b)
    - §5 "Basic Assumptions about Individuals, Attributes, and Relations" (Item 1c), 1968 (Box 20, Folder 16c)
    - §10 "One Family of Attributes" (Item 1a), 1968 (Box 20, Folder 17a)
    - §10 "One Family of Attributes" (Item 1b), 1968 (Box 20, Folder 17b)
    - §12 "Representative Functions for C" (Item 1c), 1968 (Box 20, Folder 17c)
    - First Part, §1-13, Table of Content and Corrections, 1970 (Box 20, Folder 18)
    - 1A. "Basic Concepts", 1968 (Box 20, Folder 19)
    - 1B. "Basic Axioms", 1966 (Box 20, Folder 20)
    - 2A. "Monadic Predicate Languages", 1966-1970 (Box 20, Folder 21)
    - 2B. "Stronger Languages" (Box 20, Folder 22)
    - 3A. "The Space of Models", 1966-1967 (Box 20, Folder 23)
    - 3B. "Propositions", 1966-1970 (Box 20, Folder 24)
    - 3C. "Sample Propositions and Random Variables" (Box 20, Folder 25)
    - 4A. "The Distinction Between Pure and Applied Logic", 1969 (Box 20, Folder 26)
    - 4B. "Requirements for Primitive Attributes" (Box 20, Folder 27)
    - 5. "Basic Assumptions about Individuals, Attributes and Relations" (Box 20, Folder 28)
    - 6. "Sublanguages" (Box 20, Folder 29)
    - 7. "Regular C-Functions" (Box 20, Folder 30)
    - 8. "Coherent C-functions (Box 20, Folder 31)
    - 9. "Symmetric C-functions (Box 20, Folder 32)
    - 10. "One Family of Attributes (Box 20, Folder 33)
    - 11A. MI-Functions (Box 20, Folder 34)
    - 11B. "MI-Sequences" (Box 20, Folder 35)
    - 11C. "MS- and MD-Functions (Box 20, Folder 36)
    - 12. "Representative Functions for C (Box 20, Folder 37)
    - 13. The Principle of Instantial Relevance (Box 20, Folder 38)
    - Basic System, Table of Content §13-17 (Box 20, Folder 39)
    - 14A. "The Color Space", 1968-1969 (Box 20, Folder 40)
    - 14B. "Distance and Width" (Box 20, Folder 41)
    - 14C. "Several Families", 1968 (Box 20, Folder 42)
    - 15A. "Basic Regions", 1969 (Box 20, Folder 43)
    - 15B. "Admissible Regions" (Box 20, Folder 44)
    - 16A. "Gamma- and Eta-Parameters" (Box 20, Folder 45)
    - 16B. "Rules for the Eta-Parameter" (Box 20, Folder 46)
    - 16C. "The Search for Principles of Analogy by Similarity" (Box 20, Folder 47)
    - 17A. "The Eta-Function: General Considerations" (Box 20, Folder 48)
    - 17B. "The Normal Function f", 1969-1970 (Box 20, Folder 49)
    - 17C. "The Proximity Influence" (Box 20, Folder 50)
- Carnap's Death, Politics, Graphology: Notes, Clippings, and Correspondence, 1923-1971; III.
  The majority of the documents in this series relate to Carnap's death in 1970, such as condolence letters and obituaries. A few items contain graphology studies of, among others, Carnap's handwriting from the 1920s, as well as newspaper clippings on philosophical and political issues and Bertrand Russell, and early reviews of Carnap's writings.
  Access Restrictions
  Patrons must sign the Confidentiality Agreement to view restricted materials in this series.
  - Deutsche Bank, München, 1964-1966 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Deutsche Bank, München, 1966-1969 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Deutsche Bank, Gummersbach, 1962-1964 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Agnes [Kaufmann], Business, 1963 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Agnes [Kaufmann], Business - R. C. Trust, 1964-1965 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Umzug nach Deutschland, 1969 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - R & H Wohnstift München, 1968-1969 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - RC Wohnstift Amersee Fragebogen, 1970 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Glendale Federal Savings - Home Savings, 1963-1971 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Deutsche Bank, München, 1969-1970 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Security Pacific National Bank, 1967-1971 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Security Pacific National Bank, 1967-1969 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - United California Bank, 1970 (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Deutsche Bank, München, 1964 (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Glendale Federal Savings and Loan Association, 1964-1967 (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Gift Tax & Estate Tax, 1963-1966 (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - Income Tax for 1969 (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Income Tax: General, 1966-1968 (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - Income Tax for 1970 (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - Property Tax Los Angeles, 1965-1968 (Box 21, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence with accountants, 1970 (Box 21, Folder 21)
  - Income Tax for 1968 (Box 21, Folder 22)
  - Income Tax for 1967 (Box 21, Folder 23)
  - Trusts E. C.; Income Tax 1966-67, 1967-1968 (Box 21, Folder 24)
  - Estate Tax 1965, 1964-1965 (Box 21, Folder 25)
  - Estate E. C.; Income Tax 1964-1966, 1965-1966 (Box 21, Folder 26)
  - Income Tax for 1966, 1966-1967 (Box 21, Folder 27)
  - Travel Expenses 1965; Elmau, 1964-1967 (Box 21, Folder 28)
  - Income Tax for 1965, 1965-1966 (Box 21, Folder 29)
  - Income Tax for 1964, 1964-1965 (Box 21, Folder 30)
  - Income Tax adjustments for 1961, 1961-1962 (Box 21, Folder 31)
  - Investments planning, 1967-1968 (Box 21, Folder 32)
  - Investments planning, 1966-1967 (Box 21, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence with accountant, 1957-1959 (Box 21, Folder 34)
  - Investments, 1964-1970 (Box 21, Folder 35)
  - Correspondence with accountants, 1963-1970 (Box 21, Folder 36)
  - Correspondence with accountants, 1964-1970 (Box 21, Folder 37)
  - Auto insurance, 1969 (Box 21, Folder 38)
  - Health Insurance from UCLA, 1967-1969 (Box 21, Folder 39)
  - Fire and Property Insurance, 1963-1969 (Box 21, Folder 40)
  - Automobile, 1965-1967 (Box 21, Folder 41)
  - Automobile Import Tax, 1968 (Box 21, Folder 42)
  - Retirement Annuities, 1965-1967 (Box 21, Folder 43)
  - Social Security death payout, 1970 (Box 21, Folder 44)
  - UCLA Salary, 1969-1970 (Box 21, Folder 45)
  - UCLA Salary, 1968-1970 (Box 21, Folder 46)
  - Loeb Investment Statements, 1968 (Box 21, Folder 47)
  - Loeb Investment Statements, 1966 (Box 21, Folder 48)
  - Loeb Investment Statements, 1967 (Box 21, Folder 49)
  - Loeb Investment Statements, 1969 (Box 21, Folder 50)
  - Loeb Investment Statements, 1970 (Box 21, Folder 51)
  - Correspondence with Marcus & Kahn Law Offices; Copy of Elizabeth Ina Carnap's will, with Rudolf's annotations, 1963-1964 (Box 21, Folder 52)
  - Correspondence with Marcus & Kahn Law Offices, 1965 (Box 21, Folder 53)
  - Correspondence with Marcus & Kahn Law Offices, 1966 (Box 21, Folder 54)
  - Correspondence with Abraham Marcus Law Office, 1967 (Box 21, Folder 55)
  - Medicare, 1969 (Box 21, Folder 56)
  - Medicare, 1968-1969 (Box 21, Folder 57)
  - Terminal hospital bill, 1970 (Box 21, Folder 58)
  - Medicare benefits information, 1964-1969 (Box 21, Folder 59)
  - R. C. Bookkeeping - royalities, daily expenses, donations, 1965-1970 (Box 21, Folder 60)
  - Westside Committee of Concern on Viet Nam - letter and articles, 1965-1968 (Box 21, Folder 61)
  - Carnap books donated to UCLA - photocopy of typsescript, c. 1965 (Box 21, Folder 62)
  - Clippings: Vietnam War (Box 21, Folder 63)
  - Bilanz, 1927-1961 (Box 21, Folder 64)
  - Charitable Contributions and Donations, 1963-1967 (Box 21, Folder 65)
  - Charitable Contributions and Donations, 1966 (Box 21, Folder 66)
  - Loeb: Übersichten aus Kontobuch, 1953-1964 (Box 21, Folder 67)
  - Carnap's Obituaries, 1970 (Box 21, Folder 68)
  - Trauerbriefe, 1970-1971 (Box 21, Folder 69)
  - Paper Clippings on Carnap's Death, 1970 (Box 21, Folder 70)
  - Condolence Letters, 1970-1971 (Box 21, Folder 71)
  - Newspaper Clippings Philosophy and Politics, 1968 (Box 21, Folder 72)
  - Funeral Society, 1964-1969 (Box 21, Folder 73)
  - Graphoanalyse: Alte Aufzeichnung, 1923-1930 (Box 21, Folder 74)
  - Tribute to Bertrand Russell (Box 21, Folder 75)
  - Rezensionen, 1923-1935, 1963 (Box 21, Folder 76)
- Photographs, IV.